Hi Paladin - Thanks for the comment. I did, in fact, purchase this product through Amazon and was giving a promo code by the Seller that applied a discount to the purchase at checkout. I don't know why my review isn't marked "Verified Purchase" by Amazon; I've reviewed a number of other products purchased with a discount promo code that are marked as verified and I can't seem to isolate what differs among those that are and those that aren't.

I'm an academic who doesn't make a ton of dough and I appreciate these opportunities to try out products I wouldn't ordinarily be able to try out, and in turn let the little world of Amazon know my perspective on it. I don't think of this as compensation: I think of this as a good deal on a product that I'd like to try out. And, often, the discount is similar to what you'd get on a sweet lightning deal or price drop. The fact is: The price of nearly all products fluctuates over time, sometimes dramatically, but the purchase price is not included with the review (and rarely mentioned in the review). Of course, I appreciate that price is a major factor in the decision to purchase a product. Moreover, as someone with a background in psychology, I completely recognize that receiving a product for free or at a large discount can bias even the most well-meaning of the reviewers, including myself.

So, while I am an active participant in the "discounts for reviews" economy that has emerged on Amazon, I completely acknowledge that it presents significant problems for cautious consumers like yourself. But, my view is that the Amazon review system was broken from the start. Anyone can write a review about anything at any time and for any reason, with no mechanism for verifying purchases made on Amazon, and a seemingly unreliable mechanism for verifying some purchases that were made through Amazon. All products are rated on the same general 1-5 star scale. And while it's nice that Amazon highlights the most helpful reviews for a given product, it's still the case that all ratings are weighted equally in the average rating that most customers probably sort the product list on when they are on the hunt. A 3-word review with 0 helpful votes without a verified purchase stamp receives just as much weight as a 1,000-word review with 1,000 helpful votes and a verified purchase stamp. And, reviews get up(down)voted for some reasons that have nothing to do with the value of the product, such as being funny or interesting or opinionated. 

Suffice to say, the star rating system is stupid. And Amazon's interface is insanely simplistic, making it extremely difficult for skeptical customers like yourself to filter the endless list of products and make a purchasing decision. The point I'm trying to make here is that the bulk of the blame goes to Amazon for not doing more to improve their review system, which is all the more important given how important reviews (read: stars) are for determining the success of a product. These days, a product can be tanked by a single 1-star review (which could very well be fake). In those cases, Sellers are stupid not to offer a limited number of their products at a discount to accumulate reviews from consumers who in the least they know gave their product a try. 

Personally, I put more weight on the content of individual reviews than on the average star rating. Which is why I try to include potentially useful information in my reviews - including visual aids like the video demonstration I uploaded for this product. Obviously, it's up to you to decide what to do with the information, but hopefully this response t your comment will at least clarify where I'm coming from as a consumer who participates in the "discounts for reviews" economy.